Preliminary Guide to the Royal Coronation and Jubilee Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Royal Coronation and Jubilee collection
1887-2002
MS 1812
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
The collection consists of commemorative artifacts and printed materials created to celebrate British Royal Jubilees, in particular, the Golden Jubilee of Queen Elizabeth II.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Frank Prochaska, 2002; transfer from the Zeta Collection, 2002.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by name of monarch.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of commemorative artifacts and printed materials created to celebrate British Royal Jubilees, in particular, the Golden Jubilee of Queen Elizabeth II.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research; due to the physical nature of the material, box 1 requires staff supervision.
Great Britain -- History -- Elizabeth II, 1952-; Great Britain -- History -- George V, 1910-1936; Great Britain -- History -- George VI, 1936-1952; Great Britain -- History -- Victoria, 1837-1901; Elizabeth, Queen of Great Britain, II, 1926- -- Anniversaries, etc.; George, King of Great Britain, V, 1865-1936 -- Anniversaries, etc.; George, King of Great Britain, VI, 1895-1952 -- Coronation; Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901 -- Anniversaries, etc.
- Inventory
  - Queen Elizabeth II [Golden Jubilee, 2002]
    - Artifacts [china, stuffed animal, cap, pencil, bookmark, etc.] (Box 1)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Due to the physical nature of the material in box 1, staff supervision is required.
    - Printed material
      - Book jackets (Box 2)
      - Hymn [by Andrew Motion, poet laureate; extract] (Box 2)
      - Postage stamps (Box 2)
      - Souvenir program, magazines (Box 2)
    - Textiles [calendar, wall hangings] (Box 3)
  - King George V [Silver Jubilee postage stamps, 1935] (Box 4)
  - Queen Victoria ["Queen's Jubilee at Oxford," 1887] (Box 5)
- Additional Material, 1937; Accession 2005-M-004
  Scope and Contents
  The accession consists of a small amount of documents from the coronation of George VI on May 12, 1937.
  - King George VI
    - Ceremonial, 1937 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Official Souvenir" program [2 copies], 1937 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Invitations, programs, and menus [mainly from London-area restaurants], 1937 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "The Royal Family: Coronation Yearbook", [1937 May] (Box 1, Folder 3)